<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Middleware 2020</title>
    <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io" />
    <updated>2020-11-25T00:34:19+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>rjan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://middleware2020.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Keynote: Developing and Assessing Middleware and Applications for Smart Cities</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/keynote-fabio-kon.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/keynote-fabio-kon.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-25T00:31:36+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Smart Cities combine advances in the Internet of Things, Big Data, Social&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>Smart Cities combine advances in the Internet of Things, Big Data, Social Networks, Cloud Computing, and Data Science technologies with the demand for cyber-physical applications in areas of public interest, such as Health, Public Safety, and Mobility. The end goal is to leverage the use of city resources to improve the quality of life of its citizens. Achieving this goal, however, requires advanced support for the development and operation of applications in a complex and dynamic environment. Middleware platforms can provide an integrated infrastructure that enables solutions for smart cities by combining heterogeneous city devices and providing unified, high-level facilities for the development of applications and services. Although several smart city platforms have been proposed in the literature, there are still open research and development challenges related to their scalability, maintainability, interoperability, and reuse in the context of different cities, to name a few. Unfortunately, available platforms lack extensive scientific validation. To contribute in this direction, we are working on InterSCity, a microservices-based, open-source, smart city platform that works as a middleware enabling the collaborative development of large-scale systems, applications, and services. In this talk, we present the architecture of the InterSCity platform, show examples of applications developed around it, and discuss how to assess the performance of such a platform with large-scale workloads produced via simulation based on realistic data.<br><br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1enu8m9811">About the speaker</h2>
<img class="post__image--right" src="https://www.ime.usp.br/fobos-client/obterfoto.php?cid=84724" width="150" height="200"> <br><strong>Fabio Kon</strong> is a Full Professor of Computer Science at the University of São Paulo. His research interests include Distributed, Scalable Systems, Software Engineering, Open Source, and Data Science. In recent years, Fabio has focused his research on Smart Cities (<a href="https://interscity.org/">https://interscity.org</a>), Evidence-based Public Policymaking, and DevOps. Fabio is an ACM Distinguished Scientist and wishes he had more time to play his vibraphone.</div>
<div> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Keynote: Teaching Distributed Systems in the Digital Age</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/keynote-maarten-van-steen.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/keynote-maarten-van-steen.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-25T00:34:15+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Having taught Distributed Systems for many years and confronted with having been&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p id="mcetoc_1enu8m9810">Having taught Distributed Systems for many years and confronted with having been asked to take over the course from a colleague who was retiring, I felt it was time for a change. Distributed systems have a very solid and stable basis, theoretically as well as practically (considering the many systems that have been in use for often decades). There is simply no real need to teach students what they can pick up from any reasonable textbook. The challenge in teaching Distributed Systems is to let students understand the inherent complexities: where does performance come from, where can I find the security measures, why does it hurt here when some part fails over there, and so on.</p>
<p>In this, anticipated highly interactive keynote, I'd like to discuss a completely different setup that is based on just a few principles: flip the classroom, good explanations come from thorough understanding, and understanding one problem very well is enough to open doors to understanding other issues in Distributed Systems. Rather than letting students dig into well-known problems, I believe it is extremely insightful to let them concentrate on controversial issues. Controversial because statements are made (in blogs and postings and scientific articles) about certain solutions that should be seriously questioned. Oftentimes, those statements are false or inaccurate, but it requires effort to discover why.</p>
<h1 id="mcetoc_1enu8ndaa2"> </h1>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1enu8m9811">About the speaker</h2>
<p><img class="post__image--right" src="media/files/m.r.vansteen.jpg" alt="Maarte  van Steen" width="200" height="200"><strong>Maarten van Steen</strong> has been full professor in Large-Scale Distributed Systems since 2002 and has published on a wide variety of subjects related to distributed systems. Together with Andrew Tanenbaum he has authored a reference textbook on the matter that has seen its way to many universities worldwide. He is currently Scientific Director of the Digital Society Institute of the University of Twente, in essence a virtual institute that bundles all the university's research on digitalization. Before joining Twente in 2015, he was member of the Computer Systems group at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam for some 20 years.</p>
<p>Working in the field of distributed systems ever since 1983, he continues to struggle understanding many of its aspects, especially when scalability is at stake. It is has driven him to believe that only the truly simple solutions will work and that complex solutions (including some of his own) come from a lack of understanding the essentials.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Program - Doctoral Symposium</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/program-doctoral-symposium.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/program-doctoral-symposium.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-18T10:28:03+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Tuesday, 8th December all times in CET Session 1 Session chairs: Animesh Trivedi, Arpan&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h3 id="mcetoc_1enbktm0u0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tuesday, 8th December </span></h3>
<p>all times in CET</p>
<table style="width: 100%; white-space: normal;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>8:50 - 9:00</strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;"><strong>Welcome &amp; Introduction</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>9:00 - 9:35</strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Session 1</strong></span></p>
<p><strong>Session chairs: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Animesh Trivedi, Arpan Gujarati, and Pramod Bhatotia</span></p>
<p><strong>Keynote: Lalith Suresh (VMWare Research)</strong><strong>    </strong><a href="https://lalith.in/2020/09/27/Low-Level-Advice-For-Systems-Research/"><strong>https://lalith.in/2020/09/27/Low-Level-Advice-For-Systems-Research/</strong></a></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;">9:35 - 9:45 </td>
<td style="width: 85%;">break</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>9:45 - 10:20</strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;">
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Session 2</span>  </strong><strong>(5 min per talk, ~3 min for questions)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Session chairs: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paris Carbone, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aastha Mehta, and Pramod Bhatotia</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(1) C. Berger - "Towards Environmental-Adaptive and Performance-Resilient Consensus in Distributed Ledger Technology"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(2) G. Russo - "Model-based auto-scaling of distributed data stream processing applications"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(3) V. Podolskiy - "Rubberband: Enabling Elastic Federated Learning with the Temporary State Management"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(4) M. Kamalian - "Fog Transport Mode Detection"</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>10:30 - 11:05</strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;">
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Session 3</span>  (5 min per talk, ~3 min for questions)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Session chairs: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thomas Pasquier, Antonio Barbalace,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and Ana Varbanescu</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(5) G. Frascaria - "Griffin: A Storage Service for Granular Edge Applications"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(6) S. Tavakolisomeh - "Selecting a JVM Garbage Collector for Big Data and Cloud Services"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(7) P. Eichhammer - "Towards Autonomous Security Monitoring in Internet-of-Things Infrastructures"</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(8) J. Gunasekaran - "Minimizing Cost and Maximizing Performance for Cloud Platforms"</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;">11:05 - 11:15</td>
<td style="width: 85%;">break</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>11:15 - 11:50</strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;">
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Session 4</span>  (5 min per talk, ~3 min for questions)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Session chairs: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Etienne Riviere, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anjo Vahldiek-Oberwagner, and Ana Varbanescu</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">( 9) A. Isstaif  - "Self-managed services using MirageOS unikernels"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(10) A. Khordadi - "Execution Migration of Managed Languages Programs Among Heterogeneous-ISA Processing Units"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(11) I. Zavalyshyn - "Building Private-by-Design IoT Systems"</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(12) P. Schmiedmayer - "Apodini: An Internal Domain Specific Language to Design Web Services"</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 15%;"><strong>11:50 - 12:00 </strong></td>
<td style="width: 85%;"><strong>Closing Remarks</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Video Submission Instructions</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/video-submission-instructions.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/video-submission-instructions.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-06T03:21:49+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Video Submission Deadline: November 27th, 2020 At the top right corner, select&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Video Submission Deadline: November 27th, 2020</strong></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1emdkodge0">Uploading the Video to YouTube</h2>
<ol>
<li class="p1">Sign in to <a href="https://www.youtube.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a>.</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">At the top right corner, select the Create video or more button -&gt; Upload Video</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Select the video file you would like to upload.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">While your video is being processed, click on “Details” of the video to fill in information. Your video title should be in the following format: TITLE (ACM MIDDLEWARE 2020). Note that for tracks where this is applicable (e.g., industry track), the title should contain the prefix. </p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p>In the description section, please include the track (Research, Industry, ...), paper ID (which can be found from HotCRP) and the names of the authors.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Under visibility, please select “Unlisted” or “Public”. The difference is that an unlisted video will not be indexed by the YouTube search engine. Click “Save” once done.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">You can optionally go to the “Subtitles” section to manually enter subtitles for your video, which will be displayed during the live broadcast. Please ensure the subtitles are accurate.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Once your video is available, please copy the link by viewing the video page on YouTube and sharing its link.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1emdl0gki1">Emailing the Youtube Link</h2>
<p>Email your link to <strong>middleware2020@tudelft.nl</strong></p>
<p class="p1">The email subject must be titled with your paper ID # and presenter last name:</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>MIDDLEWARE 2020 Video Link: PAPERID#_PRESENTER-LASTNAME</strong></p>
<p class="p1">The email body should contain:</p>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Paper ID and track</li>
<li class="p1">YouTube video link</li>
<li class="p1">Name of the speaker in the video</li>
<li class="p1">A short 3-4 lines biography of the speaker</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1">If you have any difficulty following these instructions, please contact the chairs of your track or the general chairs immediately.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Presentation Instructions</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/presentation-instructions.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/presentation-instructions.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-06T11:00:54+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Submission deadline for presentation videos: November 27, 2020 To ensure smooth operation&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Submission deadline for presentation videos: <strong>November 27, 2020</strong></p>
<p class="p1">To ensure smooth operation for our online program, talks are pre-recorded and uploaded to be streamed during each session. Authors must attend their respective Zoom sessions for the Q&amp;A immediately following the broadcast of their video, according to the moderation of the session chair.</p>
<p>The presentation time is <strong>10 minutes</strong> for research and industry track papers. Videos which significantly exceed this time limit can be cut off by the moderators during the presentation. The files have to be uploaded to YouTube and the video quality has to be at least HD (720p).</p>
<p>Following every presentation, there is a <strong>Q&amp;A session of 5 minutes</strong> which the author is required to attend. At the end of the session, there is a panel discussion comprising all presenters of the session. </p>
<p class="p1">Authors should treat the video recording as a direct substitute for a physical presentation. The audio should contain a spoken narration of the presentation. The accompanying video should contain a full walkthrough of the presentation slides, which are clearly visible. In addition, the presenter is strongly encouraged to overlay a thumbnail-sized camera feed showing the speaker. In addition, please add some 2-3 discussion points to your conclusion slide. As the talks are intentionally kept short for the online format, it is likely that there are points not discussed during the presentation, such as technical details or future work. Please include these in the conclusion slide to facilitate questions during the Q&amp;A.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1emdkodge0">Uploading the Video to YouTube</h2>
<ol>
<li class="p1">Sign in to <a href="https://www.youtube.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a>.</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">At the top right corner, select the Create video or more button -&gt; Upload Video</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Select the video file you would like to upload.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">While your video is being processed, click on “Details” of the video to fill in information. Your video title should be in the following format: TITLE (ACM/IFIP MIDDLEWARE 2020). Note that for tracks where this is applicable (e.g., industry track), the title should contain the prefix. </p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p>In the description section, please include the track (Research, Industry, ...), paper ID (which can be found from HotCRP) and the names of the authors.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Under visibility, please select “Unlisted” or “Public”. The difference is that an unlisted video will not be indexed by the YouTube search engine. Click “Save” once done.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">You can optionally go to the “Subtitles” section to manually enter subtitles for your video, which will be displayed during the live broadcast. Please ensure the subtitles are accurate.</p>
</li>
<li class="p1">
<p class="p1">Once your video is available, please copy the link by viewing the video page on YouTube and sharing its link.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1emdl0gki1">Emailing the Youtube Link</h2>
<p>Email your link to <strong>middleware2020@tudelft.nl</strong></p>
<p class="p1">The email subject must be titled with your paper ID # and presenter last name:</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>MIDDLEWARE 2020 Video Link: PAPERID#_PRESENTER-LASTNAME</strong></p>
<p class="p1">The email body should contain:</p>
<ul>
<li class="p1">Paper ID and track</li>
<li class="p1">YouTube video link</li>
<li class="p1">Name of the speaker in the video</li>
<li class="p1">A short 3-4 lines biography of the speaker</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1">If you have any difficulty following these instructions, please contact the chairs of your track or the general chairs immediately.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Conference Program</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/conference-program.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/conference-program.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-25T00:28:33+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     M4IoT Workshop DIDL Workshop Containers Workshop Doctoral Symposium DICG Workshop ARM&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <iframe width="800" height="600" style="border-width: 0;" src="https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?height=600&amp;wkst=2&amp;bgcolor=%23ffffff&amp;ctz=Europe%2FAmsterdam&amp;src=bWlkZGxld2FyZTIwY2FsZW5kYXJAZ21haWwuY29t&amp;color=%23BE6D00&amp;src=NnAyOWdpc2xzZDdvajBxaWExcjRibDZoODRAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;color=%231B887A&amp;src=YnVucDh2MjQ4M29lZ29tZ3BvNmZvbDJ1ODhAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;color=%230B8043&amp;src=ZzBraWkwMjhlN2VwcmQ1b2FnY2kyNmViZGdAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;color=%23F4511E&amp;src=Zmp2aWc1OGxka2kzdmc5M3Qxa2hnaXVtaGNAZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;color=%23AD1457&amp;src=aHB1M3YwcjJnNmxxZmcyOXI0NDluOXJ2MG9AZ3JvdXAuY2FsZW5kYXIuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbQ&amp;color=%234285F4&amp;showTitle=1&amp;showNav=0&amp;showDate=0&amp;showPrint=0&amp;showTabs=0&amp;showCalendars=0&amp;showTz=1&amp;title=Middleware%202020&amp;mode=WEEK&amp;dates=20201207/20201211" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
<p> </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1enble61m0" class="align-center">Detailed Program</h2>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1enblec091">Monday Dec. 7th</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.m4iot.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">M4IoT Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://didl-conf.github.io/didl4/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DIDL Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://sites.google.com/view/containers20/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Containers Workshop</a></p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1ent5tdcj0"> </h3>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1enblenrj2">Tuesday Dec. 8th</h3>
<p><a href="program-doctoral-symposium.html" title="Doctiral Symposium">Doctoral Symposium</a></p>
<p><a href="https://dicg2020.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DICG Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://armworkshop.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ARM Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.serverlesscomputing.org/wosc6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WoSC Workshop</a></p>
<p><a href="https://serial.ibr.cs.tu-bs.de/serial20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SERIAL Workshop</a></p>
<p> </p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1enblenrj2">Wednesday Dec. 9th</h3>
<table style="width: 800px; white-space: normal;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>10:00-11:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Opening and Keynote</strong> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;">Opening Middleware 2020</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><a href="keynote-maarten-van-steen.html">Keynote Maarten van Steen</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>13:00-14:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 1</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span >Prebaking Functions to Warm the Serverless Cold Start (Presenter: </span></span><span >Paulo Silva)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span >Resilient Cloud-based Replication with Low Latency (Presenter: </span></span><span >Michael Eischer)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Practical Active Revocation (Presenter: Stefan Contiu)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >secureTF: A Secure TensorFlow Framework (Presenter: Do Le Quoc)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >On Delivery Guarantees in Distributed Content-Based Publish/Subscribe Systems (Presenter: Pooya Salehi)</span> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>15:30-17:00</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Industry Track: Session </strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >mmFilter: Language-Guided Video Analytics at the Edge (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >blockNDP: Block-storage Near Data Processing (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >DiagSys: network and third-party web-service monitoring from the browser’s perspective (Presenter: Loïck Bonniot)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >HopsFS-S3: Extending Object Stores with POSIX-like Semantics and more (Presenter: Mahmoud Ismail)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Primula: a Practical Shuffle/Sort Operator for Serverless Computing (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Secure Volume Hot-plugging for Containers (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>18:00-19:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Posters and Demos</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Hierarchical Topic Aggregation for Geospatial Applications through Processing Extensions in Message Brokers (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Version Detection for Software Discovery in the Cloud (Presenter: )</span> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >DynPubSub: A Peer To Peer Overlay For Topic-Based Pub/Sub Systems Deployed at the Edge (Presenter: )</span> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Given 2n Eyeballs, All Quality Flaws Are Shallow (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Practical Trade-Offs in Integrity Protection for Binaries via Ethereum (Presenter: )</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>20:00-21:00</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Virtual Reception</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1enblenrj2">Thursday Dec. 10th</h3>
<table style="width: 800px; white-space: normal;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>10:00-11:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 2</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >MATCH: A Decentralized Middleware for Fair Matchmaking In Peer-to-Peer Markets (Presenter: Martijn de Vos)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >PipeTune: Pipeline Parallelism of Hyper and System Parameters Tuning for Deep Learning Clusters (Presenter: Isabelly Rocha)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Fast Training of Deep Learning Models over Multiple GPUs (Presenter: Xiaodong Yi)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >BoLT: Barrier-optimized LSM-Tree (Presenter: Dongui Kim)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >JellyFish: A Fast Skip List with MVCC (Presenter: Leeju Kim)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>13:00-14:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 3</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span >Consistent and Secure Network Updates Made Practical (Presenter: James Lembke</span></span><span >)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span >FLeet: Online Federated Learning via Staleness Awareness and Performance Prediction (Presenter: Georgios Damaskinos</span></span><span >)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;">TEEMon: A continuous performance monitoring framework for TEEs (Presenter: Robert Krahn)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >FeGAN: Scaling Distributed GANs (Presenter: Arsany Guirguis)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Poseidon: Safe, Fast and Scalable Persistent Memory Allocator (Presenter: Anthony Demeri)</span> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>15:30-17:00</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 4</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >WASP: Wide-area Adaptive Stream Processing (Presenter: Abhishek Chandra)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >SplitServe: Efficiently Splitting Apache Spark Jobs Across FaaS and IaaS (Presenter: Aman Jain)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >SR3: Customizable Recovery for Stateful Stream Processing Systems (Presenter: Hailu Xu)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Sledge: a Serverless-first, Light-weight Wasm Runtime for the Edge (Presenter: Gabriel Parmer)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Tackling Resource Underutilization in the Serverless Era (Presenter: Jashwant Raj Gunasekaran)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>18:00-19:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Keynote and Test of Time Award</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><a href="keynote-fabio-kon.html">Keynote Fabio Kon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;">Test of Time Award Ceremony</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>20:00-21:00</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Open Business Meeting</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;">Middleware 2021 Address</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h3 id="mcetoc_1enblenrj2">Friday Dec. 11th</h3>
<table style="width: 800px; white-space: normal;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>10:00-11:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 5</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >PASTRAMI: Privacy-preserving, Auditable, Scalable &amp; Trustworthy Auctions for Multiple Items (Presenter: Michał Król)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >A practical approach for updating an integrity-enforced operating system (Presenter: Wojciech Ozga)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Regaining Lost Seconds: Efficient Page Preloading for SGX Enclaves (Presenter: Lizhi Wang)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Improving the Restore Performance via Physical-Locality Middleware for Backup Systems (Presenter: Pengfei Li)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Xanadu: Mitigating cascading cold starts in serverless function chain deployments (Presenter: Nilanjan Daw)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>13:00-14:30</strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Research Track: Session 6</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span > Cost-Effective Data Feeds to Blockchains via Workload-Adaptive Data Replication (Presenter: Yuzhe Tang</span></span><span >)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span ><span >Mitigating Stragglers in the Decentralized Training on Heterogeneous Clusters (Presenter: Donglin Yang</span></span><span >)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >Coral-Pie: A Geo-Distributed Edge-compute Solution for Space-Time Vehicle Tracking (Presenter: Zhuangdi (Andy) Xu)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >An OpenMP Runtime for Transparent Work Sharing Across Cache-Incoherent Heterogeneous Nodes (Presenter: Robert Lyerly)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"> </td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><span >DoubleFaceAD: A New Datastore Driver Architecture to Optimize Fanout Query Performance (Presenter: Shungeng Zhang)</span> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 137.984px;"><strong>14:30 </strong></td>
<td style="width: 541.016px;"><strong>Closing Remarks</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Signup</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/signup.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/signup.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-24T18:51:20+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Subscribe* indicates required Email Address *First Name *Last Name *Institution *Contact PermissionsBy signing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <!-- Begin Mailchimp Signup Form -->
<div id="mc_embed_signup"><form id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" action="https://tudelft.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=8b14df4593c2908f160ffa9dc&amp;id=1440e76bcc" method="post" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" novalidate="" target="_blank">
<div id="mc_embed_signup_scroll">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1emaq8s9a0">Subscribe</h2>
<div class="indicates-required"><span class="asterisk">*</span> indicates required</div>
<div class="indicates-required"> </div>
<div class="indicates-required">
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Email Address <span class="asterisk">*</span></td>
<td><input id="mce-EMAIL" class="required email" name="EMAIL" type="email" value=""></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>First Name <span class="asterisk">*</span></td>
<td><input id="mce-FNAME" class="required" name="FNAME" type="text" value=""></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Last Name <span class="asterisk">*</span></td>
<td>
<div class="mc-field-group"><input id="mce-LNAME" class="required" name="LNAME" type="text" value=""></div>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Institution <span class="asterisk">*</span></td>
<td>
<div class="mc-field-group"><input id="mce-INSTITUTIO" class="required" name="INSTITUTIO" type="text" value=""></div>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<div id="mergeRow-gdpr" class="mergeRow gdpr-mergeRow content__gdprBlock mc-field-group">
<div class="content__gdpr"><label>Contact Permissions</label>
<p>By signing up, you indicate that you would like to participate and grant us the right to contact you with messages regarding the ACM/IFIP International Middleware Conference through the following channels:</p>
<fieldset class="mc_fieldset gdprRequired mc-field-group" name="interestgroup_field"><label class="checkbox subfield" for="gdpr_19840"><input id="gdpr_19840" class="av-checkbox gdpr" checked="checked" name="gdpr[19840]" type="checkbox" value="Y">Email </label></fieldset>
<p>You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the link in the footer of our emails. For information about our privacy practices, please visit our website.</p>
</div>
<div class="content__gdprLegal">
<p>We use Mailchimp as our marketing platform. By clicking below to subscribe, you acknowledge that your information will be transferred to Mailchimp for processing. <a href="https://mailchimp.com/legal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn more about Mailchimp's privacy practices here.</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div id="mce-responses" class="clear"> </div>
<!-- real people should not fill this in and expect good things - do not remove this or risk form bot signups-->
<div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;"><input tabindex="-1" name="b_8b14df4593c2908f160ffa9dc_1440e76bcc" type="text" value=""></div>
<div class="clear"><input id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button" name="subscribe" type="submit" value="Subscribe"></div>
</div>
</form></div>
<!--End mc_embed_signup-->
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Workshops</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/workshops.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/workshops.html</id>

        <updated>2020-08-22T01:58:49+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    ARM 2020: 19th Workshop on Adaptive and Reflexive Middleware Containers: 6th International&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="align-center"><a href="https://armworkshop.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ARM 2020: 19th Workshop on Adaptive and Reflexive Middleware</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://sites.google.com/view/containers20/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Containers: 6th International Workshop on Container Technologies and Container Clouds</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="http://www.dilute.no/dfsd/2020" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DFDS 2020: 3rd International Workshop on Distributed Fog Services Design</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://dicg2020.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DICG: 1st International Workshop on Distributed Infrastructure for Common Good</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://didl-conf.github.io/didl4/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DIDL: 4th Workshop on Distributed Infrastructures for Deep Learning</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="http://www.m4iot.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">M4IOT 2020: 7th International Workshop on Middleware and Applications for the Internet of Things</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://serial.ibr.cs.tu-bs.de/serial20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SERIAL: 4th Workshop on Scalable and Resilient Infrastructures for Distributed Ledgers</a></p>
<p class="align-center"><a href="https://www.serverlesscomputing.org/wosc6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WoSC: 6th Workshop on Serverless Computing</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Call for Demos and Posters</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/call-for-posters-and-demos.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/call-for-posters-and-demos.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-08T15:20:30+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Middleware 2020 will provide a forum for live software demonstrations of middleware&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="section-title-wrap mr-btm-72 text-center">
<div class="">Middleware 2020 will provide a forum for live software demonstrations of middleware applications, systems, and tools. Demos could take a wide and open-ended variety of forms. Typical examples include: (i) presentation of an application that leverages advanced middleware concepts, (ii) working through coding of an example on a novel middleware platform, or (iii) real-time visualizations of middleware system metrics under simulated workloads. Although the form may vary, demo presenters should take advantage of not being constrained by the format of a traditional slide presentation. Demos are encouraged for both early prototypes and mature technology.</div>
<div class=""> </div>
<div class="">Posters will provide an opportunity for conference attendees to learn about innovative work in progress and to preview late-breaking research results. Poster sessions will provide an informal setting for presenters to communicate ideas or results and also to collect feedback from attendees.</div>
<p align="left">Demo or poster contributions are solicited in all areas of middleware research and applications. For a list of applicable topics, please consider those from the call for papers.</p>
</div>
<div class="section-title-wrap mr-btm-72">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e755qp3j0" class="section-title mr-btm-10">Important Dates</h2>
<div class="entry-content single-entry-post">
<table align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Submission</strong></td>
<td class="align-left"><strong>Monday, September 14, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Notification</strong></td>
<td class="align-left"><strong>Monday, September 28, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Camera Ready Deadline</strong></td>
<td class="align-left"><strong>Friday, October 16, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<br>
<p>Submit your posters and demos through <a href="https://middleware20demos-posters.hotcrp.com">HotCRP</a>.</p>
<p>The authors of accepted demos and posters must prepare a single slide that provides an overview of their work which will be presented during the "1-minute madness" session that precedes the demo and poster session.</p>
<p>Accepted Demos and Posters papers will be included in the Middleware 2020 conference proceedings that will be published in the ACM Digital Library. The official publication date will be the date the proceedings are made available in the ACM Digital Library which may be up to two weeks prior to the first day of the Middleware conference. Note that the official publication date affects the deadline for any patent filings related to published work.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="section-title-wrap mr-btm-72">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e755qp3j1" class="section-title mr-btm-10">Demo Submissions</h2>
<div class="entry-content single-entry-post">
<p align="left">Submissions describing live demos should be at most 3 pages PDF using the ACM SIGPLAN style, which can be found on the <a href="https://www.acm.org/publications/proceedings-template" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ACM template page</a>. <strong>The font size has to be set to 10pt. </strong>The first two pages will include a description of the demo that will be included in the Middleware proceedings. The last page will outline aspects of the demo that will be considered during evaluation, but will not appear in the proceedings.</p>
<p align="left">Pages 1 and 2 should include the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Title of the demo (including beginning with "Demo Abstract:"),</li>
<li>Authors, affiliation, and contact information,</li>
<li>Description of the problems addressed,</li>
<li>Research and technical approach,</li>
<li>Related work with bibliography.</li>
</ul>
<p align="left">Page 3 should contain any additional information that will be used only to evaluate your demonstration proposal: it will not be part of the proceedings. For example, you may detail what you will show during the demo, provide links to additional online material related to your demo, e.g., videos, etc. You may also use this space to outline any special requirements you have for the demonstration, e.g., unusual space needs, exclusive access to a wireless channel, etc. The format of this page is at your discretion.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="mr-btm-72">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e755qp3j2" class="section-title mr-btm-10">Poster Submissions</h2>
<div class="entry-content single-entry-post">
<p align="left">Submissions describing posters should be at most 2 pages PDF using the ACM SIGPLAN style, which can found on the ACM template page. <strong>The font size has to be set to 10pt. </strong></p>
<p align="left">The submission should include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Title of the poster (beginning with "Poster Abstract:"),</li>
<li>Authors, affiliation, and contact information,</li>
<li>Description of the problems addressed,</li>
<li>Research and technical approach,</li>
<li>Any preliminary results,</li>
<li>Related work with bibliography.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>If you have questions or encounter any problems, please notify the Demo and Poster chairs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Angela Nicoara, angela.nicoara@hslu.ch</li>
<li>Ihor Khuz, Ihor.Kuz@data61.csiro.au</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Call for Workshops and Tutorials</title>
        <author>
            <name>rjan</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://middleware2020.github.io/call-for-workshops-and-tutorials.html"/>
        <id>https://middleware2020.github.io/call-for-workshops-and-tutorials.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-01T13:44:36+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    The annual ACM/IFIP Middleware conference is a major forum for the discussion&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The annual ACM/IFIP Middleware conference is a major forum for the discussion of innovations and recent advances in the design, construction, and use of middleware systems. Middleware is the software that resides between applications and the underlying architecture and platforms, often with an emphasis on networked computing. The goal of middleware is to facilitate the development of applications by providing higher-level abstractions for better programmability, performance, scalability, and security. It is a rapidly evolving and growing field.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Middleware conference traditionally includes a number of high-quality workshops and tutorials. We invite experts on related research subjects to submit one-day or half-day workshop and/or tutorial proposals within the scope of Middleware 2020. Proposed workshops and tutorials can be on any topic related to middleware, but we are particularly interested in workshops and tutorials focusing on emerging middleware areas.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Christine Julien, University of Texas, USA</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">David Eyers, University of Otago, NZ</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Middleware 2020 Workshop and Tutorial Co-Chairs</span></em></p>
<p><a href="mailto:middleware2020-workshops@cs.otago.ac.nz"><span style="font-weight: 400;">middleware2020-workshops@cs.otago.ac.nz</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="mailto:middleware2020-tutorials@cs.otago.ac.nz">middleware2020-tutorials@cs.otago.ac.nz</a><a href="mailto:middleware2020-tutorials@cs.otago.ac.nz"></a></span></p>
<p> </p>
<div class="section-title-wrap mr-btm-72">
<h2 id="mcetoc_1dp173ivl0" class="section-title mr-btm-10">Important Dates</h2>
<div class="entry-content single-entry-post">
<table align="center">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Workshop proposal submission</strong></td>
<td><strong>May 25, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Tutorial proposal submission</strong></td>
<td><strong>May 25, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Workshop proposal acceptance notification</strong></td>
<td><strong>June 1, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Tutorial proposal acceptance notification</strong></td>
<td><strong>June 1, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Workshop website and CFP online</strong></td>
<td><strong>June 15, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Workshop paper submission (approximate)</td>
<td>August 31, 2020</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Workshop paper notification (approximate)</td>
<td>September 28, 2020</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Workshop paper camera ready (firm deadline)</strong></td>
<td><strong>October 16, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Tutorial paper camera ready (firm deadline)</strong></td>
<td><strong>October 16, 2020</strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="section-title-wrap mr-btm-72">
<p id="mcetoc_1e58t1pgb2">All deadlines are 23:59 AOE.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e58t4t903"> </h2>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e58t1bk50"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workshop proposal submission</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each workshop proposal, not exceeding three pages of 11pt single-spaced text, in PDF format, should include the following information:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the title of the workshop;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the names, affiliations and e-mail addresses of the organizing committee;  </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a brief technical description of the workshop topic area; </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the history of the workshop, if applicable;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a short description of the intended format of the workshop (keynote speakers, discussions, etc.); </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a description of the intended review process;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tentative workshop paper submission and notification deadlines (Note that the latest camera-ready hard deadline for all workshop papers is October 16, 2020.);</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a brief statement of the relevance of the workshop to Middleware; </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a preliminary list of PC members that have accepted to participate in the committee.</span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each workshop will organize its own submissions and reviewing procedures and will provide its own website. A link will be provided to the workshop’s website from the Middleware 2020 website. Workshop organizers will ensure that all accepted papers are peer reviewed and will need to upload camera ready and copyright agreements of all accepted papers in a timely manner through the ACM portal. Organizers will plan their workshop’s schedule so that: (i) the paper submission deadline falls after the main conference's notification date; (ii) authors are notified no later than September 28, 2020; and (iii) authors submit their camera-ready papers no later than October 16, 2020. Accepted papers should be no longer than 6 pages in the standard ACM format. <strong>Note that at least one author on each accepted workshop paper must hold a full pre-conference registration, as must at least one workshop organiser.</strong> Workshop organizers are responsible for preparing the papers for their workshops in the format required by ACM. As in previous years, the Middleware conference organizers will provide companion proceedings including all workshop papers, which will be available in the ACM Digital Library. <strong>This is subject to the availability of their camera-ready papers by October 16, 2020.</strong></span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Middleware requires workshop organizers to use HotCRP (</span><a href="https://hotcrp.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://hotcrp.com/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) to collect submissions, manage reviewing, and facilitate collection of material for the proceedings. HotCRP is free of charge for Middleware workshops and provides many useful tools, such as to manage copyright assignment, final-version submission, PDF checking, and proceedings construction.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workshop proposals must be sent to:</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="mailto:middleware2020-workshops@cs.otago.ac.nz">middleware2020-workshops@cs.otago.ac.nz</a><a href="mailto:middleware2020-workshops@cs.otago.ac.nz"></a></span></p>
<p> </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e58t1bk51"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tutorial proposal submission</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Middleware conference traditionally includes tutorials given by renowned scientists and practitioners in their fields. We welcome tutorials on both mature and emerging topics. Tutorials may be lectures, interactive workshops, hands-on training, or any combination of the above, with a preference for ideas where there is some degree of interactivity. We especially welcome cross-disciplinary topics and innovative ways of interacting with the audience.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each tutorial proposal, not exceeding five pages of 11pt single-spaced text, in PDF format, should include the following information:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the title of the tutorial;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the names, affiliations and e-mail addresses of the tutorial presenters;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a short outline of the tutorial content;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a short description of the presenters’ experience in teaching and in tutorial presentation;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">references to previous editions of the tutorial (if applicable) including their date, venue, topics and number of participants and the motivation for the new proposal;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the type of tutorial presentation (e.g., mix of lecturing versus practical exercises);</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">any special requirements for the tutorial room;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">requirements for attendees (e.g., if attendees must bring their own laptop or other hardware, familiarity with certain technologies or topics, etc.);</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">any constraints on the maximum number of participants;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">sample video of a talk (encouraged, not required) especially for first-time tutorial presenters;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a brief statement of the relevance of the tutorial to Middleware.</span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Proposers of accepted tutorials will be asked to provide information of their tutorial for publication on the conference web site. Note that at least one author on each accepted tutorial must hold a full pre-conference registration.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tutorial proposals must be sent to:</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span><a href="mailto:middleware2020-tutorials@cs.otago.ac.nz"><span style="font-weight: 400;">middleware2020-tutorials@cs.otago.ac.nz</span></a></p>
</div>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
